Arthur Meyer Papers 5252
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Regional War Labor Board, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Correspondents include: Theodore Kheel (Regional WLB); Peter K. Hawley (CIO Labor Mb.); Meyer; Jules S. Fruind Esq. (Exec. Soc.); New York State Board of Mediation; Eric W. Doebler (UP Long Island Lighting Company); Robert Abelow (Exec. Dir. NWLB). Correspondence regarding William A. White and sons acting as agents for the Park-Lexington Co. regarding wages. S & S Corrugated Machinery Co. regarding divergence of opinions and manners of resolving problems of inflation; Public Panel Mbs. (approved) and (proposed) referrals for certification; approval of wage increase - Long Island Lighting Co., Queens Borough Gas & Electric Co. and Nassau & Suffolk Lighting Co; also contains a case in front of the NWLB between IBEW and above named companies regarding wage rate adjustment (Little Steel Formula). Memo- screening of public panel mbs; outlining of rules for processing of wage applications where in have intervened. Also, S&S Corrugated Paper Machinery to include dissenting opinion of labor mbs.
- U.S. Conciliation Service 1946 Press Wireless Inc. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  (Materials in 1 FF-2 FF pertain to following case, arbitrated by Meyer 1946). Press Wireless Inc. vs. American Communications Association, CIO 1946 on the issues of management rights and unilateral action of employer regarding layoffs, position reclassification, wages, back pay. Includes: award, and final award of arbitrator (Aug, 1946), miss. notes (no author) regarding issues, exhibits on Press Wireless case, correspondence and telegrams of Meyer, chiefly with J.A. Payne (National Pres., Commercial Telegraphers Union); Dean Dinwooday (Editor-in-chief, Bur. of National Affairs); Alfred Colby (Arbitrator); NYS Bd. Mediation; Joseph Selly (Pres. American Communications Assn.). Correspondence regarding arbitration decision, publication of arbitration decision, routine business of handling case, request for bills and information (1946)
- 1946 ASM Press Wireless Inc. 1946, exhibits and minutes. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  consists of additional materials pertaining to the above case of Press Wireless Inc. vs. American Communications Assn., 1946). Includes: 2 volumes of minutes of arbitration hearings (Aug. 19, 26, 1946) before A.S. Meyer; notes and a graph comparing average and actual volume of wordage output for non-supervisory employees vs. supervisory employees (ND) (company not mentioned).
- U.S. Conciliation Service General Electric and Westinghouse Matters, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  United Electric Radio and Machine workers of Am. (UE) and General Elective Co. (1945). Issues include: wages (elimination of sex differentials and minority hiring in rate. Included in FF are summary and conclusions, copies of correspondence between UE and GE regarding $2 per day wage increase, Papers regarding GE Decentralization Program, Agreed Statement of Facts and Requests for Order, Supplementary Recommendations, New Releases NWLB, Recommendations, Opinions (the above is contained in a folder called "Summary and Pertinent Appendices General Elections- Westinghouse"). Also, a new case docket Westinghouse and UE- Agreed Statement dates of Facts and Requests for Order. (Does material following pertain to UE or W-house?) Correspondence include: E.D. Spicer (U.P.) (G.E. Co.); Joseph Dermody (International Rep. UE); CE Wilson (Pres. G.E.); James J. Matles (Dir. Of Org. UE); WG Marshall (UP-Westinghouse Electric Corp.); Edward Matthews (International Rep.); Meyer. Also includes: Agreements- Westinghouse and UE Agreement, strike settlement agreement (Appendix and Supplement V), Agreement between Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Co. and others and UE and others and Local Supplements Sharon Wks, 1945, Agreement between Westinghouse and UE Supplement IV- supplement to 1944 agreement. Also includes: clippings, New Releases "Trends in Urban Wage Rates (NWLB) 10-1945" and put out by UE, telegrams, miss. notes relating to the case. Special report (USCS) John R. Murray- Commissioner of Conciliation, i.e. details of the case. Statements: Statement of Provision Covering the Lamp Department (regarding wages and incentives); Gwilym A. Price, Pres. of Westinghouse Electric Corp., regarding wage offer. Demands: Westinghouse; UE, Westinghouse local's comment on Co. demands. Letters: Mediators presentation of Westinghouse position in the current wage center, union response to co. proposals, mediators (Davis and Meyer) report of dispute between Westinghouse and UE; co. response to mediator's proposals. Also, info requested regarding hourly paid employees of the Westinghouse Electric Corp. and subsidiaries. Correspondents: Honorable Lewis B. Schwellenbach (Sec. Of Labor); Gwilym A. Price (Pres. of Westinghouse Electric Corp); Julius Emspak (Gen. Sec. Treas.); Edward Matthews (International Rep.); William H. Davis (arbitrator) and Meyers. Also, mediator's summary of case and miss. notes of his, miss. notes and type written notes relating to the case.
- Conciliation Service G.E. and Westinghouse Matters, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  News release: NW Stab. Bd. G.E. wage raises. Letters regarding wage increases, information requests, co. and u demands. Correspondents include: William H. Davis, Meyer, James Matles (UE), G. Price (Westinghouse).
- New York Telephone Co. and United Telephone Org. (UTO), Opinion and Award of arb., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  U claims transfer of employees constitutes a violation of those patrons of the Agreement which refer to occupational classifications. Also includes: "Submission" in the matter or Arb. Proceedings pursuant to contract between NY Tel. Co. and U.T.O.; miss. notes relating to case; routine letters regarding bills, information requests; information needed for case number of transfers, wages, summary of scheduled jobs requiring replacements of males or females; bill intro in NYS Assembly an act- "to prohibit discrimination in notes of --- because of sex and make up an appropriation to the DOL to pay expenses" i.e. pay for WK. Penciled in "Union Ex 4" transcript of Joint Conference Memo Equal pay for equal work 1 page. Penciled in Union Ex 2 Appendix C Top Basic Weekly Rates of Pay and Wage Progression. "Pencil," Ex 1 % of female clerks to total clerks Plant Departments down state areas and other such exhibits. Letters regarding position regarding transfer. Charles H. Parsons (Gen. Pres.) to OM Taylor (VP NY Telephone Co.).
- Interborough News Co. and Newspaper and Mail Deliverers Union of Greater NY and vicinity, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Award of Arbitrator and Submission, brief on behalf of the newspaper and Mail Deliverers Union of NY and vicinity, issues- wages. Also includes: miss. notes and minutes of hearing (1944). Correspondents: Louis Waldman Esq. (attn.), Harry E. Schultz Attn
- Ladies Garment Workers Assoc, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  1). American Coat and Suit Manufacturing Assoc. Fnc. and ILGWU (1945-46) before the impartial ch. of the coat and suit industry, union demand for a wage readjustment. Memo- Am. Cloak and Suit Manufacturing Assoc. 2). Memo- ILGWU and Jt. Bd. of Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers Union-Reply Memos-Memos on behalf of the Er's Assoc. with opposition to a wage readjustment. Also includes miss notes (in regard to case), memo supplementing the award, letters supplying information to various inquiries. Correspondents: Meyer and various people from the Wage Stab. Bd.
- 1947-195 Bdway Corp. and ASUY 195 Broadway Corp. EEs Council Award of Arbitration (1947) and transcripts of the case (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Issues wage and progression adjustments, changes in the length of wage progressions, wage increases. Also includes: miss. notes regarding case, correspondence regarding case, other arbitration awards (by Sidney Cohn and Meyer regarding wages and overtime) and supporting evidence (charts of wage pcall's). Correspondents: Meyer, Henry Meyer-attn., Mark Gailinghouse of the Bdway Corp
- As Meyer 195 Bdway Corp. Exhibits 1947, Union and Co. Exhibits an arbitration between the 195 Corp. and 195 Bdway Corp., EEs Council. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Includes: wage tables, contracts, and copies of BLS and CPI reports.
- Public Service Coordinated Transport & Public Service Interstate Transportation Co. & Amalgamated Association of St., Electric, Railway and Motorcoach EEs of America, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Opinion of the public mbs. of the Bd. of Arbitration. Award of Arbitration; dissenting opinion of the co. mb. Issues: wages, vacations, holidays. Also includes correspondence and miss. notes regarding the case. Chief correspondents: George W. Taylor, Ludus Research Dept., University of Pennsylvania, Meyer, Alfred H. Driscoll, Governor of New Jersey, Allan Weisenfeld, Secretary State of New Jersey and New Jersey State Bd. of Mediation
- Envelope #2 1947- Public Service Arbitration (NJSB of M) Union Exhibits and Minutes. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Stenographic transcripts NJ Statutory Bd. of Arbitration between Public Service Coordinated Transport Co. & Amalgamated Assoc. of St., Electric, Railway and Motorcoach EE's of America AFL (5 volumes). Pamphlet- Public Utility Mediation and Arbitration Laws, bit of u exhibits, folder of u exhibits, lists of wages, clauses from past contracts, co. rules.
- Envelope #1 1947- Public Service Arbitration (NJSB of M) Co. Exhibit., 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  22nd Annual Report of P.S. Corp. of NJ (1940), DOL, BLS reports, miss. notes relating to case, 28th Annual Report of Public Service Corp. of NJ (1946), Public Service Exhibits (Co. Exhibits) regarding wages, maps NY-NY area past agreements (1946).
- Transcript (3 volumes)., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations, Inc. (on behalf of various ap't house owners, managing agents) and Local 32-B Building Service EE's Int'l U (1950). "1950 Fact-Finding Bd.: Hearings Realty Advisory Bd. and Local 32-B, NYC."
- Local 32-B Exhibits., 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Includes: 1.) Agreements 1948-49 2.) Demands- Local 32-B through the wage scale committee for revision and Amendment of the apt. House Agreement to become effective 1950 3.) Eco Brief in support of the Demands of Local 32-B, Building Service EE's Union submitted by Robert Nathan Assoc. Consulting Eco. 1950 4.) Summary Brief submitted to the Fact Finding Bd. on behalf of Local 32-B, Building SEIU by Robert R. Nathan Association Consulting Eco. (1950) 5.) Tables regarding wage and hourly contract rates, changes in average annual earnings for workers in industries covered by Unemp. Jus. Laws NYS (ND) 6.) Miss. notes relating to the case (ND) 7.) Statement of Jules Backman (Assoc. Prof. Of Eco., NYU) on behalf of Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations, Inc. before the fact bd. (1950) 8.) Reply Brief on behalf of Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations, Inc. (1950) 9.) Memo: to Burton A. Zorn from Backman regarding def. of luxury apt. (1950) and summary of rent stow 10.) Chart NYC- Summary of Income and Expenses Apt. surveyed 1943-47. 11.) Statement on Rent Control submitted by Robert W. Dowling (Pres. Of City Investing Co.) NY before Senate Banking and Currency Committee (1949) 12.) News Release A.) "Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations (1950) regarding rent control B.) Statement of Positions of Realty Advisory Bd. of Labor Relations incorporated regarding current negotiations for a new apt. house labor agreement with Local 32-B, B.S. EIU, AFL 13.) Industry report- hours and earnings (1950) US DOL 14.) Summary Statement and Report Occupancy characteristics of Higher Rental Apts. in Manhattan (Deluxe Apt. Committee) (1950).
- Fact Finding Bd. (Realty Advisory Bd. and Local 32-B) Correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  "Reproduction of the NY State Residential Rent Control Law, reproduced by the Metropolitan Fair Rent Committee." An Act, "to amend the emergency housing rent control land generally, and making an appropriation for the expenses of the temporary state housing rent commission." Booklet: "State of NY," Emergency Housing, Commercial and Business Space Rent Control Laws, printed and distributed by American Banking (only daily banking newspaper) (ND). Paper: "Income Originating in all Real Estate." Operating Cost Study Residential Real Estate NY, NY (Office of the Housing Expenditure).
- NYS Bd. of Mediation 1950 RAB and Local 32-B Fact Finding Bd. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Correspondence (carbons and originals) (1950) chiefly between Meyer, Herbert Wecholer (Columbia University), Burton A. Zorn, Prof. Joseph A. Chamberlain (Legislative Drafting Research Funds Columbia), Louis J. Walinsky from Robert R. Nathan Assoc. Inc. Consulting Economist regarding routine correspondence (including information requests) effect of borrowing in the rent law part our building service report; breakdown of the average annual earnings in service occupations in NYC. Miss. copy of [Building Service Report] (ND), telegrams and clippings (1950), remarks of David Sullivan (pres. Local 32-B BSEIU at meeting State Mediation Bd.) 1950.
- Fact Finding Bd. Recommendations in the RAB and Local 32-B case., 1942-1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Before the NWLB "Dispute involving the Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations Inc. and Local 32-B of the B. SEIU Brief statement of the issues in the controversy in accordance with Rule co. of the Bd.'s Rules of Procedures." Also includes: Exhibits The Sloan Decision (1939, defines what buildings shall become signator and operate under the agreement), Demands made by the Union through the wage scale Committee for Revision and Amendment of the Sloan Agreement to become effective 1942, Sloan Agreement Renewal counter proposal from Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations to Local 32-B (1942), The A.S. Meyer Agreement (1942-45) terms agreed at as a result of his award. Also includes: counter proposals, wage scales and hours people work. Building SEIU and Realty Advisory Bd. on Labor Relations, Report of the Arbitrators (1950). (Joseph P. Chamberlain, William H. Davis, Meyer Ch.)
- Testimony (probably grievance cases) Houston, TX, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  (2 volumes), no information as to what they're really about.